# **Jonah Tabb**

jonahtabb@gmail.com 317.409.1247 Indianapolis, IN

**Linked In:** <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonahtabb">https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonahtabb</a> **GitHub:** <a href="https://github.com/jonahtabb">https://github.com/jonahtabb</a>

Portfolio: <u>itabbdev.com</u>

#### **Objectives:**

Junior Full-Stack Web Developer excited to solve problems and collaborate with experienced developers to quickly increase the value I can add to the codebase and for the customers. I work well with team members that are focused on good communication and support. Ready for a challenging career in web development, and continuing to grow my proficiency with Javascript, React, Typescript and emerging technologies.

### **Education:**

- Eleven Fifty Academy, Web Development Immersive Learning Program, Indianapolis, IN, October 2021
  - 12-week immersive learning program for Web Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project-based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding full-stack web apps.
- College of Lake County, Associate in Applied Science, Grayslake, Illinois, May 2015

### **Competencies & Functional Skills:**

Full-stack software & web design, technical project management, customer service, critical observation and thinking, creation & delivery, troubleshooting, agile methodology, continuous process improvement, server-side development, time management, effective communication, portfolio development, addressing and resolving business challenges

## **Technical Skills:**

Languages / Libraries: JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJs, React, Express, JWT, Bcrypt

Cloud Technologies: Heroku, Firebase, GitHub
Cl / CD: Agile, Scrum, Git, GitHub
Databases / ORM: PostgreSQL, Sequelize

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, APIs, Responsive Web Design

Styling Libraries: Bootstrap, Material UI

Other Technologies: Figma, Webflow, Zapier, Zenkit, Streak, Trello, Notion, Canva, Miro

### **Technical Projects:**

- Weather Watch App <a href="https://weatherwatch-abbf7.web.app/">https://weatherwatch-abbf7.web.app/</a>
  - Captured data and images from multiple API endpoints using HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap
     4, and Figma. View GitHub Repository at <a href="https://github.com/jonahtabb/api\_challenge\_2">https://github.com/jonahtabb/api\_challenge\_2</a>
- Community Compost App <a href="https://itabb-community-compost.herokuapp.com">https://itabb-community-compost.herokuapp.com</a>
  - Developed this full-stack single page, responsive app utilizing Typescript, React, React-Router, Class-Components, Bootstrap, CSS, and HTML. View GitHub Repository at <a href="https://github.com/jonahtabb/community\_compost\_client">https://github.com/jonahtabb/community\_compost\_client</a>
- Yum App <a href="https://jtabb-yum-app.herokuapp.com/">https://jtabb-yum-app.herokuapp.com/</a>
  - Group project using React and Material UI. My contributions include pagination, external REST API calls, dynamic data display, and responsive design. Tech stack includes Express.js, Sequelize, Node.js, and PostgresQL. Features also include token-based

authorization, and password encryption. View GitHub Repository at <a href="https://github.com/jonahtabb/yum-client">https://github.com/jonahtabb/yum-client</a>

## **Professional Experience:**

## Virtual Event Platform Developer, Self Employed, Indianapolis IN, Jan 2020 - Present

- Designed and developed a custom virtual on-demand documentary viewing platform for over 500 events from conception through till go-live phase using Webflow, Zapier, Zenkit, and JavaScript.
- Provided continuous improvement and adjustments to the platform in order to meet the customer requirements.
- Delivered live production support to users and customers for over 150 virtual events.
- Designed 50+ process automations for optimizing business efficiency using Zapier, JavaScript,
   Streak CRM, and other productivity integrations.

# Vegetable Grower, Mad Farmers Collective, Indianapolis, IN, Mar 2020 - Present

- Grew over 70 varieties of produce using a variety of data points and environmental factors. Advised senior members with the selection and purchase of seed, fertilizer, and equipment.
- Collaborated with a team to implement the plan for the growing season.
- Leveraged creative and flexible problem solving capabilities to address unexpected challenges.

### Farm Manager, Teter Organic Farm, Noblesville, IN, Jan 2016 - Mar 2020

- Managed production details and created business plans for over 100 sub-species of crops.
- Organized forecasts, prepared schedules, identified market demands, analyzed data, managed crop timelines, estimated yields, and maintained a proper record of crops.
- Assembled budget estimates for the higher management in order to allocate resources appropriately and meet company goals.
- Coordinated and communicated with groups of up to 150 volunteers for work days and public speaking events.
- Arranged weekly pickups of vegetables for over 65 families.

Horticulture Instructor, Oakland City University, Greencastle, IN, Nov 2015 - Dec 2016

Farm Manager, Marigold Hill Organics, Grayslake, Illinois, Mar 2014 - Oct 2015

## **Achievements & Awards:**

- Eleven Fifty Academy Core Value Award: "Learning"
- CIW Advanced HTML5 and CSS3 Specialist